A Guide to the Blacksburg Virginia Odd Fellows Records 1902-1969
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Blacksburg [Virginia] Odd Fellows Records 1902-1969
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Ms1988-009
1.4 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is without restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Blacksburg Odd Fellows lodge was probably formed in December of 1904. It was a branch of the Grand United Order of Odd Fellows, a mutual relief society for people of color.
Scope and Content Information
The Blacksburg, Virginia Odd Fellows Records consist of financial records, correspondence, minute books, brochures of several annual conferences, by-laws and odd issues of the Odd Fellows Journal for the men's lodge. There are also correspondence, minutes and financial records for the women's group - the Household of Ruth.
Organization
The records are arranged in two series - Lodge and House of Ruth, and then arranged chronologically.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Grand United Order of Odd Fellows in America. Tadmore Light Lodge #6184 (Blacksburg, Va.)
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.)
Contents List
- Box 1 1902-69
  - "Funeral Ceremony of the Use of the Lodges of the Grand United Order of Odd Fellows in America" 1902 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Tadmore Light Lodge minute book 1904-1911 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - "Third Quarterly Circular: Sub-committee of Management" 1905 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Payment Records 1905-1906 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence 1905-1906 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence 1907 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - "First Quarterly Circular: Sub-committee of Management 1907 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Payment records 1907 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Receipts 1907 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Receipts 1908-1909 (Box-folder 1-10)
  - Correspondence 1908-1909 (Box-folder 1-11)
  - Application for membership, Plymouth Christian 1910 (Box-folder 1-12)
  - Meeting minutes 1910 (Box-folder 1-13)
  - Correspondence 1910 (Box-folder 1-14)
  - Receipts 1910 (Box-folder 1-15)
  - Proceedings of the Fifth General Meeting September 12-17, 1910 (Box-folder 1-16)
  - Tadmore Light Lodge financial records 1910-1922 (Box-folder 1-17)
  - Payment records 1911 (Box-folder 1-18)
  - Receipts 1911-1919 (Box-folder 1-19)
  - Tadmore Light Lodge minute book 1912-1914 (Box-folder 1-20)
  - Tadmore Light Lodge dues record book 1912-1922 (Box-folder 1-21)
  - Ritual of the Grand United Order of Odd Fellows, Book Second 1914 (Box-folder 1-22)
  - Correspondence 1915 (Box-folder 1-23)
  - The King's Messengers (magazine), October 1916 (Box-folder 1-24)
  - Ritual of The Grand United Order of Odd Fellows, Book First 1916 (Box-folder 1-25)
  - Ledger--Officers roll 1916-1919; meeting minutes, 1942-1962 1916-1962 (Box-folder 1-26)
  - Members and semi-annual dues notebook 1917 (Box-folder 1-27)
  - "Second Semi-annual Circular: Sub-committee of Management" 1919 (Box-folder 1-28)
  - Checkbook stubs 1920-1921 (Box-folder 1-29)
  - Envelopes 1921 (Box-folder 1-30)
  - "Extract of the Biennial Report of A.T. Shirley, District Grand Secretary" 1921 (Box-folder 1-31)
  - Correspondence 1921 (Box-folder 1-32)
  - Committee of Management (correspondence) 1921-1925 (Box-folder 1-33)
  - W.E. Floding catalogs, lodge ephemera 1922 (Box-folder 1-34)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University Electric Light Department payment stubs 1922-1965 (Box-folder 1-35)
  - "Proceedings of the 10th Biennial Session and 33rd General Meeting;" Richmond, Virginia August 18-30, 1923 (Box-folder 1-36)
  - "First Semi-annual Circular: Sub-committee of Management" 1924 (Box-folder 1-37)
  - "Second Semi-annual Circular: Sub-committee of Management" 1924 (Box-folder 1-38)
  - Correspondence 1926 (Box-folder 1-39)
  - Dues records book 1926-1936 (Box-folder 1-40)
  - District Grand Lodge--correspondence 1927 (Box-folder 1-41)
  - Correspondence 1929 (Box-folder 1-42)
  - Applicant's agreement 1929 (Box-folder 1-43)
  - "First Semi-annual Circular: Committee of Management" 1930 (Box-folder 1-44)
  - [Folder removed from collection] (Box-folder 1-45)
  - "Proceedings of the 14th Biennial Session and 37th General Meeting of District Grand Lodge #15," Fredericksburg 1931 (Box-folder 1-46)
  - Correspondence 1931-1932 (Box-folder 1-47)
  - Proceedings of the 15th Biennial Session and 38th General Meeting of District Grand Lodge #15, Petersburg 1933 (Box-folder 1-48)
  - Committee of Management correspondence 1933-1934 (Box-folder 1-49)
  - Odd Fellows Journal 1934 (Box-folder 1-50)
  - Correspondence 1934 (Box-folder 1-51)
  - District Grand Lodge Correspondence 1934-1937 (Box-folder 1-52)
  - Endowment Department reports 1935-1937 (Box-folder 1-53)
  - Odd Fellows Journal March 5, 1936 (Box-folder 1-54)
  - Odd Fellows Journal May 7, 1936 (Box-folder 1-55)
  - Odd Fellows Journal July 2, 1936 (Box-folder 1-56)
  - Correspondence 1936 (Box-folder 1-57)
  - Correspondence 1937 (Box-folder 1-58)
  - Thanksgiving services and Ogden Day celebration program May 9, 1937 (Box-folder 1-59)
  - Committee of Management correspondence 1937-1939 (Box-folder 1-60)
  - 28th Biennial Movable Conference, souvenir program; Charlotte, North Carolina August 8-13, 1938 (Box-folder 1-61)
  - Correspondence 1938 (Box-folder 1-62)
  - District Grand Lodge correspondence 1938-1941 (Box-folder 1-63)
  - Envelopes 1930 (Box-folder 1-64)
  - Correspondence 1941 (Box-folder 1-65)
  - Payment records 1942 (Box-folder 1-66)
  - Correspondence 1943 (Box-folder 1-67)
  - Quarterly Bulletin February-May 1943 (Box-folder 1-68)
  - Committee of Management correspondence concerning death of Edward H. Morris February 3, 1943 (Box-folder 1-69)
  - Committee of Management correspondence 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1-70)
  - District Grand Lodge correspondence 1944-1947 (Box-folder 1-71)
  - Quarterly Bulletin February-May 1945 (Box-folder 1-72)
  - Correspondence 1945-1946 (Box-folder 1-73)
  - Endowment Department Report 1946 (Box-folder 1-74)
  - Membership Drive announcement 1946 (Box-folder 1-75)
  - District Grand Lodge correspondence 1947 (Box-folder 1-76)
  - Correspondence 1947 (Box-folder 1-77)
  - Committee of Management correspondence 1948-1949 (Box-folder 1-78)
  - 22nd Biennial Session and 45th General Meeting, correspondence; Newport News, Virginia August 23-25, 1949 (Box-folder 1-79)
  - Envelopes 1940-1949 (Box-folder 1-80)
  - Committee of Management correspondence 1950-1952 (Box-folder 1-81)
  - 23rd Biennial Session and 46th General Meeting, correspondence; Richmond, Virginia August 28-30, 1951 (Box-folder 1-82)
  - Correspondence 1951 (Box-folder 1-83)
  - District Grand Lodge correspondence 1952 (Box-folder 1-84)
  - Correspondence 1952 (Box-folder 1-85)
  - Petition for membership 1953 (Box-folder 1-86)
  - Ritual of the Grand United Order of Odd Fellows, Book First 1953 (Box-folder 1-87)
  - Committee of Management Correspondence 1953-1955 (Box-folder 1-88)
  - Correspondence 1954 (Box-folder 1-89)
  - Odd Fellows Bulletin, Spring 1954 (Box-folder 1-90)
  - Grand Lodge Session, Correspondence August 5-6, 1957 (Box-folder 1-91)
  - 26th Biennial Session of District Grand Lodge #15 and District Grand Household #11, souvenir program; Norfolk, Virginia August 5-8, 1957 (Box-folder 1-92)
  - Correspondence 1957 (Box-folder 1-93)
  - Envelopes 1950-1959 (Box-folder 1-94)
  - Receipts 1963 (Box-folder 1-95)
  - Correspondence 1969 (Box-folder 1-96)
  - Envelopes 1960-1969 (Box-folder 1-97)
- Box 2 1922, n.d.
  - Miscellaneous 1922 (Box-folder 2-1)
  - Dues records, receipts No Date (Box-folder 2-2)
  - Tadmore Light membership ribbons;Odd Fellows membership badge No Date (Box-folder 2-3)
  - Floding Company brochures No Date (Box-folder 2-4)
  - Ritual Cards No Date (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Gospel Hymns No Date (Box-folder 2-6)
  - Clearance Cards, as member credentials No Date (Box-folder 2-7)
  - Thanksgiving service program No Date (Box-folder 2-8)
  - Tadmore Light Lodge 27th anniversary announcement No Date (Box-folder 2-9)
  - Envelopes No Date (Box-folder 2-10)
- Box 3 1904-51
  - Household of Ruth--membership questionnaire 1904-1943 (Box-folder 3-1)
  - Household of Ruth--correspondence 1916 (Box-folder 3-2)
  - Household of Ruth---"General Laws and Regulations of the Household of Ruth Grand United Order of Odd Fellows in America" 1918 (Box-folder 3-3)
  - Household of Ruth--minute book 1918-1921 (Box-folder 3-4)
  - Household of Ruth--finance book 1918-1921 (Box-folder 3-5)
  - Household of Ruth--order for masonic supplies 1919 (Box-folder 3-6)
  - Household of Ruth--correspondence 1921 (Box-folder 3-7)
  - Household of Ruth--receipt 1921 (Box-folder 3-8)
  - Household of Ruth--financial records 1921-1927 (Box-folder 3-9)
  - Household of Ruth--First Annual Banquet invitation 1922 (Box-folder 3-10)
  - Household of Ruth--record book of minutes and roll of officers 1923-1935 (Box-folder 3-11)
  - Household of Ruth--District Grand Household correspondence 1924 (Box-folder 3-12)
  - Household of Ruth--correspondence 1925 (Box-folder 3-13)
  - Household of Ruth--diary, author unknown (probably from Blacksburg, VA), written during a convention in Farmville [VA] 1927 (Box-folder 3-14)
  - Household of Ruth--"General Laws and Regulations of the Household of Ruth Grand United Order of Odd Fellows in America" 1927 (Box-folder 3-15)
  - Household of Ruth--record book of taxes collected 1934 (Box-folder 3-16)
  - Household of Ruth--bill for Odd Fellows Journal Subscription 1935 (Box-folder 3-17)
  - Household of Ruth--meeting minute book 1935-1946 (Box-folder 3-18)
  - Household of Ruth--financial records 1937 (Box-folder 3-19)
  - Household of Ruth--receipt 1938 (Box-folder 3-20)
  - Household of Ruth--correspondence 1940 (Box-folder 3-21)
  - Household of Ruth--correspondence 1947 (Box-folder 3-22)
  - Household of Ruth--District Grand Household #11 correspondence 1949 (Box-folder 3-23)
  - Household of Ruth--membership credential 1950 (Box-folder 3-24)
  - Household of Ruth--excerpts from District Grand Household District Convention 1951 (Box-folder 3-25)
  - Household of Ruth--applicant's agreement No Date (Box-folder 3-26)
  - Household of Ruth--dues cards No Date (Box-folder 3-27)
- Box 4 n.d.
  - Black wool uniform coat with brass buttons and insignia BOOF